# **CETIN BASKOSE | Java Developer**

https://www.linkedin.com/in/cetin-baskose/

cetinbaskose@hotmail.com

07760670889

#### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

I have over 17 years of experience working as a Software Developer with significant experience and knowledge of **Java, Spring Boot**, **Microservices**, **GCP**, **AZURE**, Restful services, Oracle, PL/SQL Agile Scrum, Jira and TDD. I have a great track record of helping to transform projects, improve platforms and ultimately making a difference to a company's success.

#### **EDUCATION**

BEng Degree in Computer Engineering from Karadeniz Technical University (2005)

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **Open GI**

Java Developer

April 2023 – November 2023

Open GI is the insurance industry's technology partner. As a java developer I have worked onboarding truck and motorcycle products for different insurance companies. This development angular frontend Quote and Buy sites and at the backend java branding values, API calls and quote calculation.

- Worked on development of Quote and Buy websites for Truck and Motorcycle insurance products
- AngularJS as frontend and Java as a backend used in the projects. TypeScript, Json, xml heavily used for generating sites, question sets for quote and many configurations
- Tech stack used are Java 8, Azure Devops, Spring Boot, MySQL, JPA, Hibernate, TypeScript, Agile

# Changefirst

November 2022 – April 2023

Java Developer

Changefirst is an agile Change Management company they are re-imagining Change Management with digital technology. As a java backend developer, I am working on their java microservices maintenance and integration tests.

- Worked on backend microservices such as Assessments, Notification
- AWS S3, Java 11, Spring Boot, SQLServer, JPA, Hibernate, Docker, Kubernates, BitBucket
- Agile Scrum, Kanban, Jira, Wiki

## **INSHUR**

June 2021 – November 2022

Java Developer

INSHUR is an insurance company which provides insurance protection for UK/EU/US private hire drivers and couriers. As a java backend developer, I have helped their java microservices improvement, maintenance and involved all SDLC processes.

- Developing backend microservices such as Quote, Rating, Policy, Product, Renewal, Feature etc
- GCP, Java 16, Spring Boot, MongoDB NoSQL, JPA, Hibernate, Terraform, IAC, GitHub
- Agile Scrum, Kanban, Jira, Wiki

January 2021 – June 2021

## **NTT DATA Business Solutions**

Java Developer

Customer loyalty system development project

- Developing java backend services for SAP integration, Migration their customer data to our system, our system
  will provide them calculate points they earn from previous shopping trips, sends new campaign e- mails. System
  will keep previous preference so they will offer to customer.
- Mentoring new graduated developers, pair programming, developing new features, fixing bugs, refactoring not well written code.
- Technologies: Spring Boot, Restful Api, SAP Hana, SAP Cloud Foundry, Jenkins, Intellij, GitHub, Jira, Postman, Swagger

# **Heyman AI Limited**

August 2020 - January 2021

Java Developer

Digital Banking Start-Up customer related modules development project

- I worked on Customer, User, Security, Notification micro services development and improvement stages.
- Java 11, AWS S3, Spring Boot, Hibernate, JPA. Restful Api, JWT, Swagger, Docker, Maria DB, Microservices, Apache Kafta, Junit, Mochito, IntelliJ, Sonar Cube, Jenkins, Git, BitBucket, Agile, Jira, Confluence

# **GoodIdeaSoft Software Consulting**

February 2019 – August 2020

Java Developer

This is my own public limited company where I have been undertaking contract projects

• Alert rules developed for a mobile telecom company to improve service quality

JavaScript, Java 11, Spring Boot, PostgreSQL, Eclipse

- Communication device status indicator project
  - I. Network communication device slots and status information are shown interactively with React JS frontend and Java backend services
  - II. Java 11, Spring Boot, Rest, PostgreSQL, Docker, React JS
- Energy Consumption report development project

Spring Boot, Java 11, React, PostgreSQL, Docker

#### **Allianz Insurance**

August 2017 – Jan 2019

Java Developer

- I worked on the **transformation** project of their Life Insurance modules from an old **legacy** system to Allianz Business System (ABS). I was mainly responsible for the Government Regular Reporting Integration.
- I also undertook several different roles here at one time. I was a **Java** Developer but also acted as a Business Analyst and Scrum Master helping to learn business **requirements**, attending **Scrum** Master meetings and ensuring the structure is in place for development.
- Also at Allianz, I set up Agito Software's regular reporting solution from scratch, creating the **Database** structure, writing specific reporting queries and maps and **configuring** and **deploying** the front-end. This included generating data, **testing**, **validating** before scheduling daily or monthly submission to the Government Regulatory Institution for Insurance companies.

√ava 7, Java 8, J2EE, Spring Boot, Hibernate, JPA, Junit, Mockito, TDD, BDD ,SVN, Jenkins, CI/CD automation, Restful webservices, JSON, SOAP XML Webservices, JBOSS, Oracle, WebLogic, Jira, Eclipse, Postman, Toad, DBeaver, DB2, Oracle 12C, Oracle PL/SQL, SQL

## **Agito Software & Consulting**

March 2017 – August 2017

Java Developer

- I was hired by Agito to work on the Allianz Insurance project helping to customize Agito's **Government** Regular Reporting Product. Once this was completed, I helped maintain Agito's other customers which included the likes of BNP Paribas and NN Life Insurance
- Java, J2EE, SOAP, Oracle, XML Web Services, Jenkins, WebLogic, SVN, TFS, Jira, Oracle, PL/SQL

Asia Bank Senior Software Developer – Team Leader July 2007 – July 2016

- Our main focus was on **developing** and maintaining Corporate Credits modules, screens and business. We achieved this by developing programmes through C# .Net and Oracle PL/SQL, with the web environment being written in Java which is where I continued my love for Java Development.
- I was responsible for a **team** of 4 developers for around 7 years and undertook a massive transformation programme from Oracle forms to C# .Net and upgraded the Oracle DB too.
- Large part of the time was BAU, working on **Coding**, Analysis support, **testing** such as the **detection** and elimination of findings and errors and creating reports as requested by Audit companies. Other tasks included reviewing and approving the code, hiring responsibility of the team and arranging/organising projects to other members of the team to ensure all projects were completed on time.
- Java, .Net, C#, Eclipse, Visual Studio, Toad, SQL Navigator, VSS, TFS, Agile, Scrum, Waterfall, HP PPM, IBM Lotus, Oracle, PL/SQL

Gantek Teknoloji April 2007 – May 2007

Java Developer

Megakent Bilisim July 2006 – March 2007

Software Developer

Skills

Core Java: Java 7 | Java 8 | Java EE

Databases: PL/SQL | MySQL | MSSQL | Oracle | DB2 | H2 | Toad | DBeaver | SQuirrelSQL

Front End: ReactJS | Javascript

Data: Spring Boot | Spring Data | Spring Security | Hibernate | JPA | Swing

**API:** Restful | SOAP | XML Services | JSON | XML | Postman

Testing: TDD | Junit | Mockito | SonarQube

Methodologies: Agile | Scrum | Waterfall

**Project Management:** Jira | HP PPM | IBM Lotus

Other Skills: SVN | TFS | VSS | Git | Eclipse | IntelliJ | JDeveloper | Visual Studio Code | Borland C + + | N-Tier

Architecture | SOA | Microservices | OOP | JBOSS | Oracle Weblogic | Apache Tomcat | Jenkins | Maven

## **Training and Certifications**

Since moving to the UK, I have been continually improving myself, learning new skills and undertaking training and certifications to better myself and to improve my skillset. Learning is also something I can keen to do and, in the future, I will be undergoing further courses surrounding AWS and DevOps to add new skills to me repertoire.

All the below courses were provided by LinkedIn:

February 2019 Spring: Test Driven Development with Junit

**Programming Foundations: Test-Driven Development** 

**Learning Eclipse** 

March 2019 **Learning Spring with Spring Boot** 

Securing and Dockerizing Spring Boot Microservices

**Creating Your RESTful Spring Boot Microservice with JPA** 

April 2019 Java EE: Servlets and Java Server Pages (JSP)

June 2019 **Building Full-Stack Apps with React and Spring Apps** 

**React.js Essential Training** 

July 2019 **Java: Testing with Junit** 

HTML5: Structure, Syntax and Semantics

**Microservices: Asynchronous Messaging** 

December 2019 Spring: Spring Cloud